Curriculum Vitae Tupokigwe Isagah

## PERSONAL INFORMATION T

# Tupokigwe Isagah

• Auf dem Hellen Weyer 1-314, 56072 Koblenz

**+49 15778428719** 

https://isagah.github.io/

Gender Female | Marital Status Single | Date of birth 10/08/1986 | Nationality Tanzanian

#### **SUMMARY**

A research analyst enthusiast focused on designing information systems. Adept in delivering project requests ahead of schedule. Highly interested in working with enterprise architects to guide the process of planning and designing IT capabilities to meet the objectives of the organization.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 4/2015- Present

## Research Assistant/ Enterprise architect

University of Koblenz-Landau – IWVI Research Group- Germany

- Analyse technology and business challenges and provide innovative solutions
- Outline current and future vision enterprise architecture, including traceability from business and IT strategies to suggested technologies
- Performed design and system analysis, requirement definitions, interface and data architecture
- Translate user and designer requirements into design specification
- Construct a comprehensive method for planning and designing mobile public services
- Establish a metamodel for m-government service design
- Present a stakeholder engagement map for implementing m-government services
- Provide principles and guidelines for delivering innovative public services via mobile devices
- Present non-functional requirements of m-government services
- Provide an analysis of enterprise architecture and agile methods application in designing government services
- Programme committee member- ICEGOV 2018 and 2019, and HICCS 2019 conferences

## 7/2010 - 11/2015

# Assistant Lecturer

Mzumbe University- Department of Computing Science Studies-Tanzania

#### 3/2015 - 9/2015

### **Nuclear Instrumentation Research Assistant**

Tanzania Atomic Energy, Arusha (Tanzania)

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

### 2015 -- 2018

## PhD in Information System Management

University of Koblenz-Landau

Title: Framework for Designing M-government Services

## 2011 -- 2013

# MSc. in Information System

University of Osmania- GPA: 1.7/4.0 Distinction

# 2005 -- 2008

### Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communication

Curriculum Vitae Tupokigwe Isagah

University of Dar es Salaam 2.3/4.0 Upper Class Honors

## 2018 Coursera

Data-Driven Decision Making- Course by PwC

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Languages

Swahili - Mother Tongue

English - Fluent

German - Intermediate

## Computer Skills

- Microsoft Office Tools (Word, Excel, Visio, and PowerPoint)
- Microsoft Project software
- Data analysis
  - · Good command of SPSS software
  - Good command of MAXQDA software
  - Intermediate command of Python
- Programming languages
  - Java. C++- Basic user
  - PHP- Intermediate user
- Academic writing tools like Jabref, Citavi and Zotero
- SQL (intermediate level)
- Good command of online survey tool like LimeSurvey and SurveyMonkey

### Job-related skills

- Good command of:
  - The Open Group Enterprise Architecture (TOGAF)
  - Analytical and Design Thinking approaches
  - Information systems analysis, design and evaluation approaches
  - Quantitative, Qualitative and Design Science methodology
  - User-Centred design principles
  - Data sharing standards
  - Requirement analysis and management approaches
  - Stakeholder management techniques
  - Business Process Model (BPM) tools and techniques
  - Business Process Model Innovation
  - Software design and analysis, Enterprise application development, UML, and waterfall method
  - Evaluation approaches for artefacts from design science research
- Intermediate command of:
  - Agile methodologies
  - European Interoperability Framework (EIF)
  - Mobile technologies

#### Communication skills

- ■Teamwork
  - Work cooperatively with others toward accomplishment of a shared goal as opposed to working separately or competitively
  - · Blend perfectly in International groups
  - Thrive in a team environment and work well with other
- Excellent presentation, written and verbal communication skills
- Ability to communicate complex ideas in simple language
- Good experience in writing and presenting minutes of the meeting

Curriculum Vitae Tupokigwe Isagah

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **Publications**

■ Isagah, T. and Wimmer, M.A., 2018, May. Framework for designing m-government, services in developing countries. In Proceedings of the 19th Annual International Conference on Digital Government Research: Governance in the Data Age. Page(s) 44. ACM

- ■Isagah, T. and Wimmer, M.A., 2018, April. Addressing Requirements of M-Government Services: Empirical Study from Designers' Perspectives. In Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Theory and Practice of Electronic Governance. Page(s) 599 608. ACM
- Isagah, T. and Wimmer, M.A., 2017, March. Mobile Government Applications: Challenges and Needs for a Comprehensive Design Approach. In Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Theory and Practice of Electronic Governance. Page(s) 423 432
- ■Bunar, C. and Isagah, T., 2016. Assessing mobile participation: A case study of iCitizen, buycott, and Ushahidi. Electronic Government and Electronic Participation. Page(s) 599 608.